[
  {
    "question": "Which organ did Egyptians leave inside the body during mummification?",
    "a": "the lungs",
    "b": "the liver",
    "c": "the brain",
    "d": "the heart",
    "e": "the stomach",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What material did Egyptians use for Fayum portraits?",
    "a": "linen",
    "b": "plaster",
    "c": "papyrus",
    "d": "wood",
    "e": "canvas",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which factor caused Egyptian artwork to become more naturalistic?",
    "a": "Roman colonization",
    "b": "changes in religious practices",
    "c": "trade with Greece",
    "d": "access to new materials",
    "e": "scientific advancements",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the Mummy with an Inserted Panel Portrait of a Youth today?",
    "a": "the British Museum, London",
    "b": "the Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York",
    "c": "the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston",
    "d": "the Egyptian Museum, Cairo",
    "e": "the Neues Museum, Berlin",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What substance does encaustic paint use as a binder?",
    "a": "egg whites",
    "b": "wax",
    "c": "water",
    "d": "gum",
    "e": "oil",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was NOT a function of Fayum portraits?",
    "a": "to mark the burial site for visitors",
    "b": "to house the soul in the afterlife",
    "c": "to serve as a memorial to loved ones",
    "d": "to identify the deceased to the gods",
    "e": "to be a surrogate if the body was not preserved",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What document does art historian John Berger cite as contemporary to the Fayum portraits?",
    "a": "The Odyssey",
    "b": "Gospels of the New Testament",
    "c": "the Vedas",
    "d": "The Epic of Gilgamesh",
    "e": "Egyptian Book of the Dead",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the purpose of natron in mummification?",
    "a": "to keep away pests",
    "b": "to bind the linen",
    "c": "to dissolve the fat",
    "d": "to fill gaps and hollows",
    "e": "to improve the smell",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which detail on the Portrait of a Youth signifies the subject’s coming of age?",
    "a": "gilded crown",
    "b": "thin mustache",
    "c": "long eyelashes",
    "d": "glittering eyes",
    "e": "white clothing",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which person was NOT a common subject of Fayum portraits?",
    "a": "a pharaoh",
    "b": "a soldier",
    "c": "a merchant",
    "d": "a teacher",
    "e": "a priest",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was mummification important to the Egyptians?",
    "a": "They did not want to spiritually pollute the earth.",
    "b": "They wanted to preserve the memory of the deceased for the living.",
    "c": "They needed to prevent the spread of disease from decaying bodies.",
    "d": "They believed material life continued for the deceased.",
    "e": "They could not bury bodies because of the Nile’s flooding.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long did mummification take?",
    "a": "72 days",
    "b": "53 days",
    "c": "365 days",
    "d": "90 days",
    "e": "30 days",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Egyptians referred to the land of the dead as the Kingdom of",
    "a": "Anubis",
    "b": "Osiris",
    "c": "Horus",
    "d": "Serapis",
    "e": "Isis",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The subjects and design of Fayum portraits emphasize Egypt’s",
    "a": "prosperous economy",
    "b": "multicultural nature",
    "c": "scientific knowledge",
    "d": "religious piety",
    "e": "strict tradition",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The majority of ancient Egyptian art that is preserved relates to the culture’s",
    "a": "trade and economy",
    "b": "scholarly work",
    "c": "military",
    "d": "agriculture",
    "e": "funerary practices",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The era most associated with Gothic architecture did NOT feature",
    "a": "technological innovation",
    "b": "economic prosperity",
    "c": "social equality",
    "d": "deep spirituality",
    "e": "relative peace",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Gothic style developed in the region called",
    "a": "Île-de-France",
    "b": "Centre-Val de Loire",
    "c": "Hauts-de-France",
    "d": "Languedoc-Roussillon",
    "e": "Auvergne-Rhône-Alpe",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Gothic style came to be called",
    "a": "temporis opus",
    "b": "opus modernum",
    "c": "mechanica opus",
    "d": "opus dei",
    "e": "opus caeleste",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the period in which the Gothic style developed, kings",
    "a": "first granted rights to common citizens",
    "b": "conquered increasingly large territories",
    "c": "first claimed divine right",
    "d": "were frequently overthrown",
    "e": "became hands-on with their empires",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "During which of the following periods did the Gothic style flourish?",
    "a": "Post-classical period",
    "b": "Early modern period",
    "c": "Early Middle Ages",
    "d": "the Dark Ages",
    "e": "High Middle Ages",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following artists coined the term 'Gothic'?",
    "a": "Duccio di Buoninsegna",
    "b": "Giorgio Vasari",
    "c": "Konrad Witz",
    "d": "Cimabue",
    "e": "Gentile da Fabriano",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gothic architecture primarily differs from Romanesque in its",
    "a": "vaults",
    "b": "arches",
    "c": "decorations",
    "d": "doorways",
    "e": "columns",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pointed arches in Gothic architecture allowed architects to create",
    "a": "heavier roofs",
    "b": "smaller foundations",
    "c": "wider structures",
    "d": "thicker walls",
    "e": "larger window openings",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flying buttresses were used for the first time in",
    "a": "the Cathedral of Notre-Dame",
    "b": "Châlons Cathedral",
    "c": "Chartres Cathedral",
    "d": "Cologne Cathedral",
    "e": "St. Vitus Cathedral",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gothic architects building a cathedral were MOST likely to use",
    "a": "twin-walls",
    "b": "post-and-lintel construction",
    "c": "rib vaults",
    "d": "thin joint masonry",
    "e": "domes",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following monks wrote the handbook De diversis artibus?",
    "a": "Hugh of Saint-Victor",
    "b": "Theophilus Presbyter",
    "c": "William Durandus",
    "d": "Leonce Crenier",
    "e": "Bernard of Clairvaux",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Gothic era, making stained glass required all of the following materials EXCEPT",
    "a": "metal oxides",
    "b": "silica",
    "c": "potash",
    "d": "lime",
    "e": "granite",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the window-making process, a glazier",
    "a": "colors the glass",
    "b": "paints details onto the window",
    "c": "cuts the windowpanes with iron shears",
    "d": "designs the window",
    "e": "flattens the sheets of glass",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms refers to the act of fusing one layer of colored glass onto another?",
    "a": "\"flashing\"",
    "b": "\"transfusing\"",
    "c": "\"enameling\"",
    "d": "\"glazing\"",
    "e": "\"melding\"",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following steps in making stained glass comes LAST?",
    "a": "designing the window on a wooden panel",
    "b": "cutting the window into the right shape",
    "c": "fusing the layers of colored glass",
    "d": "painting details onto the window",
    "e": "\"leading\" the window",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  }
]

